Scholastica Olanrewaju (MPH, PMP®)

Project Manager with 8+ years of experience and proven success in healthcare projects

♦ https://solanrewaju.github.io
♦ https://www.linkedin.com/in/solanrewaju/
♦ s.olanrewaju.17@aberdeen.ac.uk

PROFILE SUMMARY

Certified Project Management Professional (PMP®) and Data Analyst with a Master of Public Health (MPH) and 8+ years of experience implementing high-impact healthcare projects. Proven success in building digital tools to optimise and/or improve processes in health information systems. I led projects that evaluated viral load test turnaround time, increased accuracy of data entry by 90%, cut analysis time by 96% and built electronic medical records (EMR) system

SKILLS AND ACCOMPLISHMENTS

Project Management: Certified PMP with experience in implementing healthcare and EHR projects including:

- Collaborated in a team of software engineers and end-users in a digital health project to design, implement, and deploy customised DHIS2 instance- for reporting, analysis, and dissemination of data using the Agile methodology
- Managed the development of a data exchange system to automate data entry into funder's data reporting
 platform through the product life cycle using waterfall methodology. This increased accuracy of data
 entry by 90% while saving 160 person-hours per reporting cycle

Data Analytics, and Visualisation: technical experience analysing and visualising large datasets for data-driven decision making, program improvement, reporting, research, and knowledge sharing

- Performed data analyst projects detailed in my website https://solanrewaju.github.io
- Contributed to the development of an R programming package- tidyNDR to analyse patient-level data sets- https://cran.r-project.org/web/packages/tidyndr/index.html

Research:

- Conducted a study to assess inter-pregnancy interval in Scotland by performing secondary data analysis
 of 588,086 records using SPSS
- Led user research to study (qualitative) the viral load test turn-around time for clients on HIV treatment. Recommendations from the study led to a **12% increase in test coverage**

Strong communication skills: Demonstrated by several artefacts including Nigeria's HIV Health Sector Annual Report (2018) which I co-authored with a joint team of government, private sector, and interagency groups. Facilitated several trainings at local and national levels

Interpersonal Skills: Excellent ability to collaborate, engage and work efficiently-independently and with teams (virtually or in-person) to achieve results.

Digital Skills: The following skills as demonstrated in my career history and projects.

- Advanced Knowledge: Microsoft Office- Excel, PowerPoint, Word, MS Office Online and DHIS2
- Working Knowledge: Microsoft Power BI, SQL, Python, Trello, Slack and Teams
- Basic Knowledge: R, SPSS, Nvivo, Tableau and Jira

WORK EXPERIENCE

Institute of Human Virology Nigeria (IHVN), Abuja

Senior Program Officer- Strategic Information (SI),

August 2020 - Present

Head-hunted by a former employer (IHVN) to return to its strategic information team

- Conceptualised and spearheaded a digital health project that built a desktop application written in Python to automate the analysis of KPIs resulting in reduced analysis time by 96% (from 4 hours to 5 minutes!) while increasing accuracy
- Led quarterly DQA projects developed protocol, created and maintained project plans, designed an Excel-based data quality assessment (DQA) tool, tracked implementation, wrote, and shared final report with stakeholders

- Analysed patient data for KPIs and monitored progress of project deliverable.
- Managed stakeholders, provided subject matter expertise and technical support to government at national and state levels
- Developed schedules, determined resources, generate budgets, tracked projects, and met deadlines on overlapping projects in fast-paced environment. Used Trello, and Microsoft to-do to keep organised

Center for Integrated Health Programs (CIHP), Abuja

Established an accomplishments-driven career highlighted by rapid acceleration (in 6 months) to increasingly responsible position. Held the following job titles:

Strategic Information Officer,
 Senior Strategic Information Associate,
 January 2020 – August 2020
 July 2019 – January 2020

- Developed curriculum and facilitated capacity building trainings of health care workers and relevant stakeholders which **strengthened the capacity of over 300** personnel
- Collaborated in multidisciplinary teams for proposal development/grant applications by conducting needs assessment, developing logic model development, theory of change and designing the information systems. A Group ANC program we designed received funding from Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation (BMGF)
- Managed the end-end transition of a health program providing treatment to 35,000+ patients in Lagos State - developed methodology/protocol, managed the development of an assessment app, supported recruitment, trained the team, wrote standard operating procedure (SOP), conducted hospital assessment, analysed data, and wrote a final report
- Led a study (qualitative) the viral load test turn-around time for clients on HIV treatment. Recommendations from the study led to a **12% increase in test coverage**

Institute of Human Virology Nigeria (IHVN), Abuja

Repeatedly recognized for top performance through fast-track promotions and selection for high-priority initiatives. Held the following job titles before leaving for graduate study

Program Officer - SI,
 Program Assistant - SI,
 April 2016 – September 2017
 March 2013 – March 2016

Monitoring and Evaluation (M&E) Support - SI,
 May 2012 – February 2013

- Collaborated with remote teams for gathering, cleaning, analysis and use of HIV/AIDS program data while ensuring high quality data verified by quality assurance procedures under strict timeline
- Designed and/or maintained up-to-date databases, dashboards and visualisations for performance measurement and program memory
- Developed reporting tools for data collection and management at facility level leveraging data validation to reduce data entry errors.

EDUCATION

University of Aberdeen, United Kingdom

Master of Public Health – MPH (with Commendation), November 2018

University of Ibadan, Nigeria

Bachelor of Science – B.Sc. Zoology (with First Class), September 2011

Others

Become a Product Manager	Udemy (online)	February 2022
PMP Exam Prep Seminar	Udemy (online)	November 2020
Data Analyst Nanodegree	Udacity (online)	September 2020
Introduction to Qualitative Research and Qualitative Data Analyses Software Course	Research Hub	March 2019
M&E of Public Health Programmes	Ahmadu Bello University	November 2015